smcvt.edu 2018-05-24

# Privacy Policy | Saint Michael's College

This statement tells you how this site uses any information we collect about you.

The policy of Saint Michael's College is to respect the privacy of all visitors to our site, to the extent permitted by law and consistent with our network operations: we will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute to anyone outside the College your personally identifiable information except when required to by proper legal authority.

This online privacy statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this website collects information and the uses to which that information will be put.

### Network Traffic

In the course of ensuring network security and consistent service for all users, the College employs software programs to monitor network traffic, identify unauthorized access or access to nonpublic information and to detect computer viruses and other software that might damage College computers or the network. In the course of such monitoring, these programs may detect such information as e-mail headers, addresses from network packets and other information. Information from these activities is used only for the purpose of maintaining the security and performance of the College's networks and computer systems. Personally identifiable information from these activities is not released to external parties without your consent unless required by law.

### Web Visit Logs

College websites routinely collect and store information from online visitors to help manage those sites and improve service. This information includes the pages visited on the site, the date and time of the visit, the Internet address (URL or IP address) of the referring site, the domain name and IP address from which the access occurred, the version of browser used and the capabilities of the browser, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, Remarketing, GDN Impression Reporting, and DoubleClick Campaign Manager integration. We may be notified if you reach this site via advertising campaign. This site makes no attempt to identify individual visitors from this information. Using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads.

### Cookies

Cookies are pieces of information stored by your web browser on behalf of a website. Portions of this site may use cookies to carry data about your current session at the site from one web page to the next, and to provide customized content once you personalize the website. We use third-party service providers to serve our ads across the internet. As you browse our website, advertising cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. This enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with our website. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address, or telephone number. If you would like to opt out of targeted advertising from Saint Michael's College, click here. (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>)

If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may turn them off in your browser, or may set your browser to ask you before accepting a new cookie. 

### Information Voluntarily Provided by You

In the course of using this website, you may choose to provide us with information to help us serve your needs. For example, you may send us electronic mail (through a mailer or a web form) to request information, you may sign up for a mailing list, you may personalize the site or you may send us your address so we may send you an application or other material. Any personally identifiable information you send us will be used only for the purpose indicated. Requests for information will be directed to the appropriate staff to respond to the request, and may be recorded to help us update our site to better respond to similar requests. We will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute your personally identifiable information without your consent, except to the extent required by law. We do not retain the information longer than necessary for normal operations. If you do not wish to have the information used in that manner, you are not required to provide it. Please contact the person listed on the specific page with questions or concerns on the use of personally identifiable information.

### External Links

College websites provide links to other websites or resources. We do not control these sites and resources, we do not endorse them, and we are not responsible for their availability, content or delivery of services. In particular, external sites are not bound by the College's online privacy policy; they may have their own policies or none at all. Since we cannot guarantee the same level of privacy and security of these sites, we recommend that you read their privacy policies, which may differ from ours.
